<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Huiba Li]]></title>
  <link href="http://lihuiba.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lihuiba.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-11T21:28:22+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://lihuiba.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Huiba Li]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Pages]]></title>
    <link href="http://lihuiba.github.io/blog/2014/02/11/github-pages/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-11T10:19:39+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lihuiba.github.io/blog/2014/02/11/github-pages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Github provides web site hosting service for projects as well as users or
organizations. The hosting service supports only static pages, so we have
to generate the .html files from markdown files before uploading them. The
page contents are also controlled by git, so uploading is done by <code>git
commit</code> and <code>git push</code>.</p>

<p>Project site can be automatically generated by an <strong>Automatic Page Generator</strong>
in <strong>repository setting</strong>. By convention, project site is located on the
project&rsquo;s <strong>gh-pages</strong> branch. We can switch to that branch by <code>git checkout
gh-pages</code>. The site can be also manually created, by creating the gh-pages
branch. The site URL will be <a href="http://username.github.io/projectname/.">http://username.github.io/projectname/.</a></p>

<p>User or organization site is created by creating a repository named
<strong><em>username</em>.github.io</strong>, and the site URL will be
<a href="http://username.github.io/.">http://username.github.io/.</a></p>

<p>Github web site hosting service supports custom domain names. The detailed
instruction can be found at <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/setting-up-a-custom-domain-with-pages.">https://help.github.com/articles/setting-up-a-custom-domain-with-pages.</a></p>

<p>We can write blog using simple Markdown syntax, and use <strong>Jekyll</strong> to generate
.html files from markdown files. See <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/quickstart/">http://jekyllrb.com/docs/quickstart/</a> for
detail. We can further use <strong>octopress</strong> to help us handling HTML templates,
CSS, Javascripts and setting up our configuration. See <a href="http://octopress.org/">http://octopress.org/</a>
for detail.</p>

<p>Other things about github pages, such as custom 404 page, can be found at
<a href="http://octopress.org/.">http://octopress.org/.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
